<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2017 06 on Zack&#39;s Notablog</title><link>/written/2017-06/</link><description>Recent content in 2017 06 on Zack&#39;s Notablog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 09:51:22 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/written/2017-06/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beware of the free trial</title><link>/beware-of-the-free-trial/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 09:51:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>/beware-of-the-free-trial/</guid><description>I was looking at my bank statement last week and something was wrong. I had a charge of $15 for The Service (a big company that I will not name here), a service I hadn&amp;rsquo;t used for years after I tried one of their free items. Did I cancel it? No, I didn&amp;rsquo;t think so. But also, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember actually signing up for it.
It got worse. Looking back at my previous statements I saw that I was also charged the previous month as well.</description></item><item><title>Recursive ingredients</title><link>/recursive-ingredients/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 19:19:15 -0700</pubDate><guid>/recursive-ingredients/</guid><description>What would happen if you made a recipe out of the ingredients for a recipe? What if you repeated this process over and over? I ended up doing this and generated the recipe that starts with the most basic ingredients - dirt, water and sun.
Here are the ingredients of my favorite recipe - a recipe for bread - that I have made almost every week during the past decade:</description></item><item><title>Watercoloring with neural networks</title><link>/watercolor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 05:48:49 -0700</pubDate><guid>/watercolor/</guid><description>Can a neural network help me improve my art? Could I take a photo, paint it, and then use a neural network to render the original photo in the style of my painting to make it better? Could I learn something from it?
Some background I started thinking about these questions because I’ve been reading about neural networks, and I’ve seen a lot of these neural networks create new works of art by rendering a photo in the style of a famous painting1.</description></item><item><title>Autological words and quines</title><link>/quines/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 09:48:59 -0600</pubDate><guid>/quines/</guid><description>The word &amp;ldquo;noun&amp;rdquo; is a singular word. It is the only word that is what it is. Such a word is an &amp;ldquo;autological word&amp;rdquo; as they posses the property that they express. To determine if X is autological, it requires answering yes to any of the following questions:
Is X a X word? Is &amp;ldquo;X&amp;rdquo;, X? Some great examples of autological words are &amp;ldquo;polysyllabic&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;unhyphenated&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;harmless&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;pentasyllabic&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;unique&amp;rdquo;.</description></item></channel></rss>