<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Zack&#39;s Notablog</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on Zack&#39;s Notablog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 05:40:05 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Recursive recipes</title><link>/recursive-recipes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 05:40:05 -0700</pubDate><guid>/recursive-recipes/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve thought a lot about the recipe when making food.1 Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about what kind of recipe you need to truly make something from scratch. To truly make a recipe from scratch you need only a few ingredients: sun, water, soil, and seeds.2 I previously made a website with various recipes that lets you see the work flows for creating different foods from scratch.3 I&amp;rsquo;ve now created another website, recursive.</description></item><item><title>Installing Keybase on Chromebook</title><link>/installing-keybase-on-chromebook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 10:28:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>/installing-keybase-on-chromebook/</guid><description>Keybase is a great system for mounting a end-to-end encrypted filesystem. It also has an encrypted git feature which is great for storing secure information in repositories. While keybase has releases for most systems, that don&amp;rsquo;t have any releases for armh, of which Chromebooks fall.
With help from the keybase developers I have determined a way to get keybase up and running on a Chromebook in no time.
First install the pre-requisites:</description></item><item><title>My Favorite Vimrc</title><link>/my-favorite-vimrc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 10:25:45 -0700</pubDate><guid>/my-favorite-vimrc/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying writing in vim a lot more. There is a nice and simple way to make writing a lot easier (word-wrapping, nice color scheme). You can just make the following config file (save as ~/.vimrc):
func! WordProcessorMode() set columns=80 setlocal formatoptions=1 setlocal noexpandtab map j gj map k gk setlocal spell spelllang=en_us set complete+=s set formatprg=par setlocal wrap setlocal linebreak set foldcolumn=3 highlight Normal ctermfg=black ctermbg=grey hi NonText ctermfg=grey guifg=grey endfu com!</description></item><item><title>Hugo Craft</title><link>/hugocraft/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 23:12:08 -0600</pubDate><guid>/hugocraft/</guid><description>This is a ready-to-go Hugo-based blog publishing system. The styling has a lot of inspiration from the blog of Chris Siebenmann which I think excels in simplicity and minimalism. It uses mage for an OS-agnostic build system to make it easy to chain commands. It has a simple search and comments ready-to-go.
Features Integrated search (try it) Integrated comments at the bottom of each post Automatic image captioning using markdown Very fast (base page ~3.</description></item><item><title>Shallow `go get`</title><link>/shallow-go-get/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 07:00:57 -0700</pubDate><guid>/shallow-go-get/</guid><description>This is a little hack to use shallow clones for new git checkouts with go get. Unfortunately for Gophers, this has been an open issue for three years counting without a workable solution aside from patching the go toolchain yourself. This solution utilizes a git wrapper that determines if a pull/clone is happening and then makes sure it is shallow.
The wrapper is only a few lines of code, here&amp;rsquo;s the main.</description></item><item><title>Painters &amp; Hackers</title><link>/hackers-and-painters/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 22:22:02 -0700</pubDate><guid>/hackers-and-painters/</guid><description>Hacking1 and painting2 are both hobbies for me. I write programs for myself, to make things easier or just because they are fun to write. Few of these programs are useful3. More often I write useless programs, like a program to determine if random squiggles generate random numbers4. I started painting and coding about fifteen years ago5 for my own enjoyment. Along the way, though I&amp;rsquo;ve found some interesting comparisons about the reception of paintings and programs and whats it like to interact with other hackers and painters.</description></item><item><title>Painting of Red Heifer</title><link>/painting-red-heifer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 00:16:52 -0700</pubDate><guid>/painting-red-heifer/</guid><description>I started out with this great photo by James Wheeler.
I started out by sketching out the painting, loose white paint on red.
The background went very quickly, but I like how it turned out.
I spent most of the time on the head, but I think the light colors came out well.
If you have a picture that you&amp;rsquo;d like me to paint, leave a comment below.</description></item><item><title>Painting of roof with cats</title><link>/painting-roof/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:16:52 -0700</pubDate><guid>/painting-roof/</guid><description>I recently completed my biggest painting ever, 24&amp;rdquo; by 36&amp;rdquo; canvas with acrylic. I started out with a red canvas because I like how it can surround paintings to make them a little bolder (see some of my other paintings with a red background).
I picked out the starting picture - of a lone cat on a tiled roof in Jarandilla de la Vera, Spain. The original picture was taken by Fernando Nieto (check out his 500px, its great!</description></item><item><title>Analyzing 15 marathons over 4,000 days</title><link>/marathons-2018/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 23:07:45 -0700</pubDate><guid>/marathons-2018/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve done dozens of races and about 15 marathons since I started running. I&amp;rsquo;ve plotted my pace for 15 official marathons. Its quite obvious now that I&amp;rsquo;ve plateaued at a nominal pace. You can see that I got fast quite quickly - after about three years I hit my plateau of about 8 minutes per mile.
In my first three years of running I ran about 20 miles a week - sometimes more, sometimes less.</description></item><item><title>Average chocolate chip cookies</title><link>/average-cookies/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 20:57:15 -0700</pubDate><guid>/average-cookies/</guid><description>I recently wrote a program to determine consensus recipes. It scrapes the web for a thousand recipes for a given recipe (e.g. cookies), then clusters the recipes and finally computes an average ingredient list for each cluster. This idea was prompted by making brownies, because I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure whether to use cocoa, chocolate, or both. Turns out there is a recipe for each variation of brownie.
I decided to try out my software in the real world.</description></item><item><title>Consensus cookery</title><link>/consensus-cookery/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 09:41:01 -0600</pubDate><guid>/consensus-cookery/</guid><description>Sometimes when I want a recipe to cook something new I will find several recipes for the same thing and try to use them as a guide to generate an average or &amp;ldquo;consensus&amp;rdquo; recipe. This code should make it easy to generate consensus recipes (useful!) and also show variation between recipes (interesting!).
Finding a consensus recipe requires first clustering many recipes. This is because a single recipe (e.g. a recipe for brownies) might have many significant variations (e.</description></item><item><title>FIND3</title><link>/find3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 09:41:01 -0600</pubDate><guid>/find3/</guid><description>There is a new version of FIND now, called &amp;ldquo;FIND3.&amp;rdquo; Its public on Github now.
FIND is the Framework for Internal Navigation and Discovery. It is basically an indoor GPS for your house or business, using only a simple smartphone or laptop.
This is an idea I started thinking about 8 years ago and wrote the first code in PHP almost four years ago, dubbed version 0, as a proof-of-concept.</description></item><item><title>Code I wrote</title><link>/code-i-wrote/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 05:48:49 -0700</pubDate><guid>/code-i-wrote/</guid><description>In 2017, I wrote 17 programs. Some or neat tools, some are playthings, and some are libraries for Go.
howmanypeoplearearound (2,967 stars) Count the number of people around you 👨 ‍ 👨 ‍ 👦 by monitoring wifi signals 🛰. PIanoAI (233 stars) Realtime piano learning and accompaniment from a Pi-powered AI 🎹. progressbar (215 stars) A really basic thread-safe progressbar for Golang applications. croc (207 stars) Easily get things from one computer to another 🐊.</description></item><item><title>Anonymous nonfiction</title><link>/anonfiction/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 07:16:03 -0700</pubDate><guid>/anonfiction/</guid><description>Sarcasm is the native language of the Internet. Unfortunately, since sarcasm is a close friend to cynicism, this can make the Internet a negative and disillusioning place. I decided to make an effort to make a place on the Internet that is more positive and reflective. This place would be where you can present your own story, anonymously and sincerely. The result was initially called &amp;ldquo;Stories, Incognito&amp;rdquo; but I later decided on the name &amp;ldquo;anonfiction&amp;rdquo; (i.</description></item><item><title>Podcasts I heard</title><link>/podcasts-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 09:41:01 -0600</pubDate><guid>/podcasts-2017/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve spent days sitting in a dark room looking into a microscope. Lots of the time I listen to music, but I&amp;rsquo;ve started to listen to podcasts. I&amp;rsquo;ve found a lot of great podcasts out there. I think my number one category of podcast is “the podcast about the small things.” Its always a welcome relief from the mainstream media which focuses more on the hyperbole of small things. I do like some news, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found some great podcasts that pitch the news in a more informal and friendly way.</description></item><item><title>Books I read</title><link>/books-2017/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 09:41:01 -0600</pubDate><guid>/books-2017/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve read about 15 books this year - not as many as I&amp;rsquo;d like (I read 40 in college), but I did a lot of magazine reading too (e.g. The Sun and The New Yorker). The books that I read can be classified into three major categories: non-fictional animal encounters, magical horror realism and fictional non-fiction.
The first main category are books I read in 2017 are about non-fictional animal encounters.</description></item><item><title>Painting from computer-generated primitives</title><link>/painting-primitives/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 18:25:57 -0700</pubDate><guid>/painting-primitives/</guid><description>Computers can do many amazing things with art, especially with the advent of neural networks1. In 2016, I saw some computer-generated art that inspired me to generate art as a human. The art I saw was a rendition of photos in primitives. Here&amp;rsquo;s an example (For much more, just follow @primitivepic):
These kinds of photos were generated using a computer program that tries to replicate a photo by slowly building up primitive shapes (ellipses, rectangles, triangles) of a single color until eventually enough different shapes and colors converge on the original image.</description></item><item><title>How to easily make nested templates (Go)</title><link>/golang-nested-templates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 04:50:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>/golang-nested-templates/</guid><description>https://play.golang.org/p/OVkruYsBVV
package main import ( &amp;#34;bytes&amp;#34; &amp;#34;fmt&amp;#34; &amp;#34;log&amp;#34; &amp;#34;text/template&amp;#34; ) type View struct { Title string Content string } func main() { header := ` {{define &amp;#34;header&amp;#34;}}&amp;lt;head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;{{ $.Title }}&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt; {{end}}` page := ` This line should not show {{define &amp;#34;indexPage&amp;#34;}}&amp;lt;html&amp;gt; {{template &amp;#34;header&amp;#34; .}}&amp;lt;body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;{{ .Content }}&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/html&amp;gt; {{end}}` view := View{Title: &amp;#34;some title&amp;#34;, Content: &amp;#34;some content&amp;#34;} // Here we try to set which page to view as content t := template.</description></item><item><title>Odd one out</title><link>/odd-one-out/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 12:01:10 -0600</pubDate><guid>/odd-one-out/</guid><description>Being the &amp;ldquo;odd one out&amp;rdquo; means that you differ from all other people in some way. Its pretty easy to feel like the the odd one out in your family. Lots of families might have the one child who is left-handed, or the father who converted to Christianity. Its also easy to feel like the odd one out in your community. You might be known as the math teacher that climbs mountains or the guy that rollerblades without a shirt while playing guitar.</description></item><item><title>Send a file with netcat</title><link>/send-with-netcat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 04:15:10 -0600</pubDate><guid>/send-with-netcat/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned how to send a file with IPFS and also how to send a file with an assortment of modern techniques. Here&amp;rsquo;s yet another method to send a file. It&amp;rsquo;s only a line of bash, and you can get a nice progress bar and upload to any server that is listening on a certain TCP port.
On the server computer, server.com, that is receiving the file, just do:
netcat -l -p 6000 &amp;gt; somefile On the other computer that is sending the file just do:</description></item><item><title>Look ma, no hard disk</title><link>/just-ram/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 04:51:39 -0600</pubDate><guid>/just-ram/</guid><description>I had a bad habit of leaving everything in my Downloads folder, and never clearing anything out. I might need it, assume, at some point. However, this is never true. To get myself out of this &amp;ldquo;I might need it*&amp;rdquo; mindset, I started deleting my Downloads/ folder every time I start my computer. This way, I had to remember, that anything I put in there would disappear when I turned my computer off.</description></item><item><title>Sending a file in 2017</title><link>/sending-a-file/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 20:11:36 -0600</pubDate><guid>/sending-a-file/</guid><description>My good friend Jessie and I want to watch a documentary movie on turkeys together.1 I have the file on my computer and she does not, so I want to send this file to her directly2 from my computer. There are a couple of restrictions though:
the turkey documentary is a ~1 GB file Jessie lives 2,000 miles away in a different country Jessie uses Windows OS Jessie is not a programmer, and avoids anything that involves running something on the command-line How should I send the movie, in the fastest possible way, so we can start learning about turkeys together?</description></item><item><title>Send a file with IPFS</title><link>/ipfs-transfer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 21:27:07 -0600</pubDate><guid>/ipfs-transfer/</guid><description>Sending a file with IPFS is fun (after all it is leveraging the peer-to-peer network and content-addressable blocks of data!) and easy.
Install IPFS Here is the basic instructions to install:
wget https://dist.ipfs.io/go-ipfs/v0.4.11/go-ipfs_v0.4.11_linux-amd64.tar.gz tar -xvzf go-ipfs* cd go-ipfs sudo ./install.sh ipfs init ipfs config Addresses.Gateway /ip4/0.0.0.0/tcp/9001 ipfs config Addresses.API /ip4/0.0.0.0/tcp/5001 The last two lines are useful for listening on LAN connected devices. The port 0.0.0.0 will let run the IPFS daemon on a different computer but still use the peer-to-peer portal from that computer.</description></item><item><title>Most sentences are unique</title><link>/sentences/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 21:16:56 -0600</pubDate><guid>/sentences/</guid><description>How long does a sentence have to be to gaurantee its uniqueness? This question can be answered by looking at a huge corpora of indexed sentences, e.g. the text of the internet. All that has been written on the internet is not nessecarily a million monkeys typing on a keyboard (although a million monkeys typing on a keyboard could produce all the current content),1 with exception of a website that generates random text.</description></item><item><title>Using crawdad</title><link>/crawdad/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 20:03:10 -0600</pubDate><guid>/crawdad/</guid><description>crawdad is a simple, yet powerful alternative for scraping in a distributed, persistent manner (backed by Redis). It can do simple things, like generating site maps. It can also do complicated things, like extracting all the quotes from every page on a quotes website (tutorial follows).
Install First get Docker which will be used for running Redis.
Then you can simply download crawdad:
$ wget https://github.com/schollz/crawdad/releases/download/v3.0.0/crawdad_3.0.0_linux_amd64.zip $ unzip crawdad*zip $ sudo mv crawdad*amd64 /usr/local/bin/crawdad Unlike many other scraping frameworks, crawdad is a single binary that has no dependencies.</description></item><item><title>Read news in the terminal with Docker</title><link>/docker-news/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 05:44:33 -0600</pubDate><guid>/docker-news/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on readable, a simple bookmarklet for easily reading articles in the browser (Github). As part of this, I made a Docker image that utilizes Mozilla&amp;rsquo;s readability package.
You can easily use the Docker image to directly read articles from the command line.
First pull it.
$ docker pull schollz/readable Then set a URL that contains a news article:
$ URL=http://www.cnn.com/2017/10/03/world/nobel-physics-prize-2017/index.html Then read!
$ docker run --rm -t schollz/readable $URL | more ---------------------------------------------------------- Nobel Prize in Physics goes to &amp;#39;black hole telescope&amp;#39; trio ---------------------------------------------------------- Story highlights - The development proves Einstein&amp;#39;s prediction of gravitational waves - More than 1,000 people worked on the technology over four decades (CNN)The 2017 Nobel Prize in Physics has been awarded to Rainer Weiss, Barry C.</description></item><item><title>Automatic captioning of images using Javascript</title><link>/captioning-images/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 13:55:03 -0600</pubDate><guid>/captioning-images/</guid><description>I like to caption my images and I like to write in Markdown. However, it is currently not possible to make captioned images, i.e. make an HTML figure using just Markdown - at least at the current spec (version 0.27) at the time of this writing. Of course, Markdown supports HTML, so you could just write a &amp;ldquo;&amp;lt;figure&amp;gt;&amp;rdquo; tag everywhere instead of writing with the Markdown &amp;ldquo;![]()&amp;rdquo; image syntax. However, I want to use the &amp;ldquo;!</description></item><item><title>How much ice do you need?</title><link>/ice-cubes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 09:43:35 -0600</pubDate><guid>/ice-cubes/</guid><description>MathJax.Hub.Config({ tex2jax: { inlineMath: [[&#39;$&#39;,&#39;$&#39;], [&#39;\\(&#39;,&#39;\\)&#39;]], displayMath: [[&#39;$$&#39;,&#39;$$&#39;], [&#39;\[&#39;,&#39;\]&#39;]], processEscapes: true, processEnvironments: true, &#34;HTML-CSS&#34;: { linebreaks: { automatic: true } }, SVG: { linebreaks: { automatic: true } }, skipTags: [&#39;script&#39;, &#39;noscript&#39;, &#39;style&#39;, &#39;textarea&#39;, &#39;pre&#39;], TeX: { equationNumbers: { autoNumber: &#34;AMS&#34; }, extensions: [&#34;AMSmath.js&#34;, &#34;AMSsymbols.js&#34;] } } }); MathJax.Hub.Queue(function() { // Fix tags after MathJax finishes running. This is a // hack to overcome a shortcoming of Markdown.</description></item><item><title>Use social media without being social</title><link>/using-social-media/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 09:04:40 -0600</pubDate><guid>/using-social-media/</guid><description>Social media seems to be more about creating a persona that voicing your thoughts and ideas. Not thinking about public opinion enables you too emit thoughts without fear of judgment, which is why I&amp;rsquo;ve found it helpful to use social media without being social.
I make accounts on social media that are totally protected. I don&amp;rsquo;t follow anyone or let anyone follow me. I keep the account locked so no one can even visit it.</description></item><item><title>OSS divisions</title><link>/oss/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 09:04:40 -0600</pubDate><guid>/oss/</guid><description>There are two reasons I think its good for everyone to have a good division between &amp;ldquo;personal&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;corporate&amp;rdquo; use for open-source software (OSS).
If you, the OSS maintainer, are compensated, everyone benefits. While your time spent coding your OSS is valuable, I think the frictionless delivery of new features and bug fixes is something that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t go away. Since I&amp;rsquo;m not actively supporting you financially to work on this, I can only hope that someone does so I can benefit.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 09:04:10 -0600</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>My name is Zack and I am an academic scientist and programmer.
This site has my notes on interesting recent science and my adventures in coding and art (which often overlap).
I&amp;rsquo;ve made other sites, including a list of my open-source projects, my academic page, my smart Raspberry Pi projects, essays on afrofuturism, book suggestions, music suggestions, movie suggestions and a recursive recipe cookbook.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>/contact/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 09:04:10 -0600</pubDate><guid>/contact/</guid><description>Please feel free to get in touch. Send me your thoughts or questions, any thoughts or questions at all.
Email me at zack dot scholl at gmail dot com. Tweet me @yakczar. Keybase chat me @schollz. I will probably be able to respond to most interactions within 72 hours.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>/projects/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 09:04:10 -0600</pubDate><guid>/projects/</guid><description>This is a list and description of the 40 projects that I created that I still maintain, ordered in terms of popularity (e.g. Github stars).
find (4,275 stars) High-precision indoor positioning framework for most wifi-enabled devices. howmanypeoplearearound (2,967 stars) Count the number of people around you 👨 ‍ 👨 ‍ 👦 by monitoring wifi signals 🛰. find-lf (437 stars) Track the location of every Wi-Fi device (:iphone:) in your house using Raspberry Pis and FIND.</description></item><item><title>Beware of the free trial</title><link>/beware-of-the-free-trial/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 09:51:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>/beware-of-the-free-trial/</guid><description>I was looking at my bank statement last week and something was wrong. I had a charge of $15 for The Service (a big company that I will not name here), a service I hadn&amp;rsquo;t used for years after I tried one of their free items. Did I cancel it? No, I didn&amp;rsquo;t think so. But also, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember actually signing up for it.
It got worse. Looking back at my previous statements I saw that I was also charged the previous month as well.</description></item><item><title>Recursive ingredients</title><link>/recursive-ingredients/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 19:19:15 -0700</pubDate><guid>/recursive-ingredients/</guid><description>What would happen if you made a recipe out of the ingredients for a recipe? What if you repeated this process over and over? I ended up doing this and generated the recipe that starts with the most basic ingredients - dirt, water and sun.
Here are the ingredients of my favorite recipe - a recipe for bread - that I have made almost every week during the past decade:</description></item><item><title>Watercoloring with neural networks</title><link>/watercolor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 05:48:49 -0700</pubDate><guid>/watercolor/</guid><description>Can a neural network help me improve my art? Could I take a photo, paint it, and then use a neural network to render the original photo in the style of my painting to make it better? Could I learn something from it?
Some background I started thinking about these questions because I’ve been reading about neural networks, and I’ve seen a lot of these neural networks create new works of art by rendering a photo in the style of a famous painting1.</description></item><item><title>Autological words and quines</title><link>/quines/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 09:48:59 -0600</pubDate><guid>/quines/</guid><description>The word &amp;ldquo;noun&amp;rdquo; is a singular word. It is the only word that is what it is. Such a word is an &amp;ldquo;autological word&amp;rdquo; as they posses the property that they express. To determine if X is autological, it requires answering yes to any of the following questions:
Is X a X word? Is &amp;ldquo;X&amp;rdquo;, X? Some great examples of autological words are &amp;ldquo;polysyllabic&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;unhyphenated&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;harmless&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;pentasyllabic&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;unique&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Why Go?</title><link>/why-go/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 09:48:59 -0600</pubDate><guid>/why-go/</guid><description>Lots of people ask me this question, and I end up writing the same answer over and over. I just wrote my plain answer here so I can just link to it. Don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to ask me other questions, though if you need. The basic answer is: because of time and money.
Coding in Go saves me time. When I write code, I often write run the program periodically to test it.</description></item><item><title>Moderation</title><link>/moderation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 09:43:35 -0600</pubDate><guid>/moderation/</guid><description>This quote by Oscar Wilde,
Everything in moderation, including moderation
is wrong.
By doing everything in moderation &amp;ndash; including moderation &amp;ndash; then that means you are overdoing moderation, which the quote forbids.
It should be amended:
Everything in moderation, excepting moderation</description></item><item><title>Using Wordpress with Docker</title><link>/wordpress-on-docker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 13:54:51 -0600</pubDate><guid>/wordpress-on-docker/</guid><description>I like wordpress, but it is very intensive to get working, as it uses a lot of PHP and requires SQL. Of course, nowadays you can do everything in Docker, so here is my method for getting wordpress to work great on Docker.
Using Docker, I was able to get 2 blogs run on the smallest DigitalOcean droplet (which was already running two dozen other things). Each blog required 360MB of RAM, and the total Docker space was 3.</description></item><item><title>Skip swiping with adb and bash</title><link>/skip-swiping/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 06:41:49 -0600</pubDate><guid>/skip-swiping/</guid><description>Like many, I&amp;rsquo;ve used dating apps (Tinder / Bumble / OkCupid) to find potential dates. I was annoyed at having to swipe right on a lot of people who would probably never respond to me after I swiped right. It seemed to me to be a waste of time to swipe through those people who would not actually be available in my dating pool. I&amp;rsquo;d rather only view a pool of people who respond to me so we can open a dialog right away to see whether we would match.</description></item><item><title>How do interleaved phonebooks stay together?</title><link>/interleaved-phonebooks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/interleaved-phonebooks/</guid><description>We have all marveled at the astonishing feat of being able to hold up massive amounts of weight with only phonebooks. Mythbusters even went so far as to use tanks to try to pull apar the phone books. Since then, however, the origin of this phenomenon has remained very elusive and escaped full description.
It was first thought that the mechanism is due to the friction between interleaving pages. A new paper by Hector Alacron and colleagues1 finds that this explaination is incorrect and offer a more intuitive and more predictive explaination.</description></item><item><title>What is bitcoin?</title><link>/bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bitcoin/</guid><description>(Yes, yet another description of how Bitcoin works)
Standard currencies like USD, Yen, Euro&amp;rsquo;s all have a central bank associated with them that can print and distribute money at their whim. Bitcoins are a special type of currency - a cryptocurrency that is completely decentralized. Instead of a bank manager looking over the system and injecting cash when needed, the decentralized currency system monitors and regulates itself! How is this possible?</description></item><item><title>A possible cure for cataracts</title><link>/cataracts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/cataracts/</guid><description>Cataracts are the clouding of the lens in the eye which can lead to blindness or can severely impair sight. Cataracts are most commonly associated with age, but there are about 20 million people on Earth that were born with cataracts. The cause of these congenital cataracts are varied but most suggest that its the crystallin proteins themselves that get mutated. (1) The eye produces these crystallin proteins that are supposed to last a lifetime, so when they are mutated they become unstable and cause cataracts!</description></item><item><title>Ants thrive in the Sahara desert</title><link>/ants/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ants/</guid><description>There is a class of ants that survive in the Sahara desert despite it being one of the hottest places on Earth, where the surface temperature can reach up to 150 degrees Fahrenheit. These ants, called &amp;ldquo;silver ants&amp;rdquo; or Cataglyphis bombycina have recently been found to harbor specialized triangular hairs that enable them significantly increased thermoregulation, as reported in the recent issue of Science. [1] Though the surface of the desert exceeds 150F, the ants can keep an internal temperature of 120F.</description></item><item><title>Proteins can tune their folding to circadian rhythms</title><link>/protein-switching/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/protein-switching/</guid><description>Proteins are central to biology. For the most part, proteins in the body are crucial for catalyzing reactions that carry out almost all of our biologial processes. For a protein to be useful, after it&amp;rsquo;s made by a ribosome, it needs to fold into a 3-dimensional structure that is unique to its sequence.
Its been widely thought that every unique sequence corresponds to a single unique structure. However, in biology, there are always exceptions to the rule.</description></item><item><title>The brain is like crumbled paper</title><link>/brain-folds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/brain-folds/</guid><description>This paper shows that the crumpling of our brain is much simpler than we thought . The crumples in our brain are just like the ones in crumpled paper. Bruno Mota and Suzana Herculano-Houzel find that our brain shares something in common with crumbled balls of paper - both did not evolve their folds in response to natural selection of their environment.
This paper shows that the crumpling of our brain is much simpler than we thought.</description></item><item><title>Animal language vs. human language</title><link>/b11653e28c3d45b3267a760d386d1849/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/b11653e28c3d45b3267a760d386d1849/</guid><description>Language is an extremly important aspects of our human lives, and its aquisition might be an innate part of our brain that separates us from animals. However, different animals can understand language on different levels, as noted by Steven Pinker in his book The Language Instinct:
The most receptive trainee for an artificial language with a syntax and semantics has been a parrot; the species with the best claim to recursive structure in its signaling has been the starling; the best vocal imitators are birds and dolphins; and when it comes to reading human intentions, chimps are bested by man&amp;rsquo;s best friend, Canis familiaris.</description></item><item><title>Protein folding, simulation vs. experiment</title><link>/simulation-and-experiment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/simulation-and-experiment/</guid><description>Prigozhin et al. has brought simulations and experiments of protein dynamics closer together than ever before. They do this by creating a clever new protein that gives more detailed experimental insight and simulations on a state-of-the-art molecular dynamics supercomputer. Their insights add another brick into the path that scientists have been building for decades to bridge protein experiments and simulations. The only way to do this are through advances like this paper - creating experiments that are faster than ever before while creating simulations that can simulate reality for longer than ever before.</description></item><item><title>Making a brain from scratch</title><link>/neuron-origin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/neuron-origin/</guid><description>No one knows where neurons, the basic of human thought, come from. They are thought to have evolved once throughout the animal kingdom and perfected ever since. However, the newly revealed DNA sequencing of a comb jelly called &amp;ldquo;Pacific sea gooseberry&amp;rdquo;1 indicates this is not the case, as it has evolved its own neural system independently of any other sea jelly.
The brain is one of the most complex components of any anatomical system, maybe the most complicated thing in the universe - consisting of neurons, cerebral tissue, neurotransmitters, etc.</description></item><item><title>Smelling bone marrow transplants</title><link>/sense-of-smell/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/sense-of-smell/</guid><description>I just recently wrote about a recent discovery that find people can smell without their noses (hint they use their skin) . Well, a new article by Lavi Secundo et. al. finds that the nose is still useful, since the olfactory receptors in a nose are so unique that they can distinguish humans from one another and this distinction can be used to find bone marrow transplant donors! [1]</description></item><item><title>Driving forces of bitcoin</title><link>/bitcoin-forces/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bitcoin-forces/</guid><description>A recent article published in PloS ONE attempts to figure out the origin of the rise in value of bitcoin. [1] The author, Ladislav Kristoufek, dissects the most probable sources of Bitcoin valuation influences using a special technique - cross wavelet transforms. This technique decomposes signals into the frequency domain and allows one to look at correlations between two sets of time-series data over various cycle lengths (e.g. daily or monthly or yearly) over time.</description></item><item><title>Downloading sounds from the JS-8</title><link>/js8/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 13:54:40 -0600</pubDate><guid>/js8/</guid><description>Boss makes a really cool Audio player with guitar effects, the JS-8. It turns out that some of the cool sounds that is has can be downloaded directly via a little hacking. ​ ​ You&amp;rsquo;ll need to create a fake JS-8 device. To do this you basically download the backup data and then format a thumbdrive so that it looks like a JS-8 device.
First download eBand JS-8 factory installed data in the included SD Card.</description></item><item><title>Understanding human mortality through worms</title><link>/worm-mortality/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/worm-mortality/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s very bold to invent a new word. Its even more bold to invent a new word and add that as a keyword of your science article! That&amp;rsquo;s exactly what Ankita Bansala, Lihua Zhua, Kelvin Yena, and Heidi Tissenbaumam did in their paper1 on which they question the value of the term &amp;ldquo;lifespan&amp;rdquo; and probe key assumptions using worms. Their newly invented term, gerospan, shows up about 34 times and, though they don&amp;rsquo;t say exactly where it comes from, it seems to be a mashup of the more common &amp;ldquo;lifespan&amp;rdquo; with the department of one of the authors (Gerontology, which means - literally - the study of old people).</description></item><item><title>Smelling with skin</title><link>/skin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/skin/</guid><description>We smell with our nose, or do we? Recently scientists have found that for some smells we can smell with our skin, and those smells can heal wounds. Our ability to smell requires olfactory receptors which are often found in the nose. Humans have about 400 of these receptors, 350 of which are in the nose, while others have been shown to exist in sperm, the prostate, intestines, and kidneys.</description></item><item><title>Books I read</title><link>/books-2008/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2008 15:00:45 -0700</pubDate><guid>/books-2008/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a comprehensive list of all the books that I read in 2008. This list does not include Sherman&amp;rsquo;s Lagoon or Get Fuzzy comic books, and it does not include textbooks.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ten Commandments (for a scientist)</title><link>/ten-commandments/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 15:19:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>/ten-commandments/</guid><description>Moses reached upon Mt. Sinai and was given the gift of the Ten Commandments which have dictated the fundamental rules of life ever since. Scrawled on the back of the Ten Commandments was actually another set of commandments that determined the virtuousness of science and the held commandments to follow when Moses led his people to the promised land to live fruitfully in the pursuit of scientific knowledge.
I. Thou shalt always vortex thy cells.</description></item><item><title>Genesis</title><link>/genesis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2008 21:54:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>/genesis/</guid><description>In the beginning, 10 to 20 times 109 years ago, there was a big bang. A hundredth of a second later electrons, photons and neutrinos appeared. Three minutes later the quarks of the fundamental particles formed into light nuclei, approximently 76% Hydrogen and 24% Helium. 300,000 years later G-d said, &amp;ldquo;Let there be light&amp;rdquo;; and the nuclei combined with electrons to form neutral atoms, making the universe transparent to photons.</description></item><item><title>Hash v.2</title><link>/hash2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2007 13:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>/hash2/</guid><description> var SHA512 = new Hashes.SHA512; function display(text) { $(&#39;#form&#39;).fadeOut(&#39;slow&#39;, function() { $(&#39;#outputBox&#39;).text(text); $(&#39;#outputContainer&#39;).fadeIn(&#39;slow&#39;); }); }; function unpack(str) { var bytes = []; for(var i = 0; i 8); bytes.push(char &amp; 0xFF); } return bytes; } function pack(bytes) { var str = &#34;&#34;; for(var i = 0; i Hash Another document.getElementById(&#34;inputtext&#34;).focus();</description></item><item><title>Hash v.1</title><link>/hash/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2007 13:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>/hash/</guid><description> var SHA512 = new Hashes.SHA512; function display(text) { $(&#39;#form&#39;).fadeOut(&#39;slow&#39;, function() { $(&#39;#outputBox&#39;).text(text); $(&#39;#outputContainer&#39;).fadeIn(&#39;slow&#39;); }); }; function unpack(str) { var bytes = []; for(var i = 0; i 8); bytes.push(char &amp; 0xFF); } return bytes; } function pack(bytes) { var str = &#34;&#34;; for(var i = 0; i Hash Another document.getElementById(&#34;inputtext&#34;).focus();</description></item><item><title>Search Results</title><link>/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/search/</guid><description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml ` [outputs] home = [&amp;quot;HTML&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;JSON&amp;quot;] \`</description></item></channel></rss>