<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2015 on Zack&#39;s Notablog</title><link>/written/2015/</link><description>Recent content in 2015 on Zack&#39;s Notablog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/written/2015/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How do interleaved phonebooks stay together?</title><link>/interleaved-phonebooks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/interleaved-phonebooks/</guid><description>We have all marveled at the astonishing feat of being able to hold up massive amounts of weight with only phonebooks. Mythbusters even went so far as to use tanks to try to pull apar the phone books. Since then, however, the origin of this phenomenon has remained very elusive and escaped full description.
It was first thought that the mechanism is due to the friction between interleaving pages. A new paper by Hector Alacron and colleagues1 finds that this explaination is incorrect and offer a more intuitive and more predictive explaination.</description></item><item><title>A possible cure for cataracts</title><link>/cataracts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/cataracts/</guid><description>Cataracts are the clouding of the lens in the eye which can lead to blindness or can severely impair sight. Cataracts are most commonly associated with age, but there are about 20 million people on Earth that were born with cataracts. The cause of these congenital cataracts are varied but most suggest that its the crystallin proteins themselves that get mutated. (1) The eye produces these crystallin proteins that are supposed to last a lifetime, so when they are mutated they become unstable and cause cataracts!</description></item><item><title>Ants thrive in the Sahara desert</title><link>/ants/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ants/</guid><description>There is a class of ants that survive in the Sahara desert despite it being one of the hottest places on Earth, where the surface temperature can reach up to 150 degrees Fahrenheit. These ants, called &amp;ldquo;silver ants&amp;rdquo; or Cataglyphis bombycina have recently been found to harbor specialized triangular hairs that enable them significantly increased thermoregulation, as reported in the recent issue of Science. [1] Though the surface of the desert exceeds 150F, the ants can keep an internal temperature of 120F.</description></item><item><title>Animal language vs. human language</title><link>/b11653e28c3d45b3267a760d386d1849/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/b11653e28c3d45b3267a760d386d1849/</guid><description>Language is an extremly important aspects of our human lives, and its aquisition might be an innate part of our brain that separates us from animals. However, different animals can understand language on different levels, as noted by Steven Pinker in his book The Language Instinct:
The most receptive trainee for an artificial language with a syntax and semantics has been a parrot; the species with the best claim to recursive structure in its signaling has been the starling; the best vocal imitators are birds and dolphins; and when it comes to reading human intentions, chimps are bested by man&amp;rsquo;s best friend, Canis familiaris.</description></item><item><title>Downloading sounds from the JS-8</title><link>/js8/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 13:54:40 -0600</pubDate><guid>/js8/</guid><description>Boss makes a really cool Audio player with guitar effects, the JS-8. It turns out that some of the cool sounds that is has can be downloaded directly via a little hacking. ​ ​ You&amp;rsquo;ll need to create a fake JS-8 device. To do this you basically download the backup data and then format a thumbdrive so that it looks like a JS-8 device.
First download eBand JS-8 factory installed data in the included SD Card.</description></item></channel></rss>