<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thoughts on Your website</title><link>/tags/thoughts/</link><description>Recent content in Thoughts on Your website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 23:12:08 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hugo Craft</title><link>/hugocraft/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 23:12:08 -0600</pubDate><guid>/hugocraft/</guid><description>This is a ready-to-go Hugo-based blog publishing system. The styling has a lot of inspiration from the blog of Chris Siebenmann which I think excels in simplicity and minimalism. It uses mage for an OS-agnostic build system to make it easy to chain commands. It has a simple search and comments ready-to-go.
Features Integrated search (try it) Integrated comments at the bottom of each post Automatic image captioning using markdown Very fast (base page ~3.</description></item><item><title>Painters &amp; Hackers</title><link>/hackers-and-painters/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 22:22:02 -0700</pubDate><guid>/hackers-and-painters/</guid><description>Hacking1 and painting2 are both hobbies for me. I write programs for myself, to make things easier or just because they are fun to write. Few of these programs are useful3. More often I write useless programs, like a program to determine if random squiggles generate random numbers4. I started painting and coding about fifteen years ago5 for my own enjoyment. Along the way, though I&amp;rsquo;ve found some interesting comparisons about the reception of paintings and programs and whats it like to interact with other hackers and painters.</description></item><item><title>Anonymous nonfiction</title><link>/anonfiction/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 07:16:03 -0700</pubDate><guid>/anonfiction/</guid><description>Sarcasm is the native language of the Internet. Unfortunately, since sarcasm is a close friend to cynicism, this can make the Internet a negative and disillusioning place. I decided to make an effort to make a place on the Internet that is more positive and reflective. This place would be where you can present your own story, anonymously and sincerely. The result was initially called &amp;ldquo;Stories, Incognito&amp;rdquo; but I later decided on the name &amp;ldquo;anonfiction&amp;rdquo; (i.</description></item><item><title>Podcasts I heard</title><link>/podcasts-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 09:41:01 -0600</pubDate><guid>/podcasts-2017/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve spent days sitting in a dark room looking into a microscope. Lots of the time I listen to music, but I&amp;rsquo;ve started to listen to podcasts. I&amp;rsquo;ve found a lot of great podcasts out there. I think my number one category of podcast is “the podcast about the small things.” Its always a welcome relief from the mainstream media which focuses more on the hyperbole of small things. I do like some news, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found some great podcasts that pitch the news in a more informal and friendly way.</description></item><item><title>Books I read</title><link>/books-2017/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 09:41:01 -0600</pubDate><guid>/books-2017/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve read about 15 books this year - not as many as I&amp;rsquo;d like (I read 40 in college), but I did a lot of magazine reading too (e.g. The Sun and The New Yorker). The books that I read can be classified into three major categories: non-fictional animal encounters, magical horror realism and fictional non-fiction.
The first main category are books I read in 2017 are about non-fictional animal encounters.</description></item><item><title>Odd one out</title><link>/odd-one-out/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 12:01:10 -0600</pubDate><guid>/odd-one-out/</guid><description>Being the &amp;ldquo;odd one out&amp;rdquo; means that you differ from all other people in some way. Its pretty easy to feel like the the odd one out in your family. Lots of families might have the one child who is left-handed, or the father who converted to Christianity. Its also easy to feel like the odd one out in your community. You might be known as the math teacher that climbs mountains or the guy that rollerblades without a shirt while playing guitar.</description></item><item><title>Most sentences are unique</title><link>/sentences/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 21:16:56 -0600</pubDate><guid>/sentences/</guid><description>How long does a sentence have to be to gaurantee its uniqueness? This question can be answered by looking at a huge corpora of indexed sentences, e.g. the text of the internet. All that has been written on the internet is not nessecarily a million monkeys typing on a keyboard (although a million monkeys typing on a keyboard could produce all the current content),1 with exception of a website that generates random text.</description></item><item><title>Use social media without being social</title><link>/using-social-media/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 09:04:40 -0600</pubDate><guid>/using-social-media/</guid><description>Social media seems to be more about creating a persona that voicing your thoughts and ideas. Not thinking about public opinion enables you too emit thoughts without fear of judgment, which is why I&amp;rsquo;ve found it helpful to use social media without being social.
I make accounts on social media that are totally protected. I don&amp;rsquo;t follow anyone or let anyone follow me. I keep the account locked so no one can even visit it.</description></item><item><title>OSS divisions</title><link>/oss/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 09:04:40 -0600</pubDate><guid>/oss/</guid><description>There are two reasons I think its good for everyone to have a good division between &amp;ldquo;personal&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;corporate&amp;rdquo; use for open-source software (OSS).
If you, the OSS maintainer, are compensated, everyone benefits. While your time spent coding your OSS is valuable, I think the frictionless delivery of new features and bug fixes is something that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t go away. Since I&amp;rsquo;m not actively supporting you financially to work on this, I can only hope that someone does so I can benefit.</description></item><item><title>Beware of the free trial</title><link>/beware-of-the-free-trial/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 09:51:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>/beware-of-the-free-trial/</guid><description>I was looking at my bank statement last week and something was wrong. I had a charge of $15 for The Service (a big company that I will not name here), a service I hadn&amp;rsquo;t used for years after I tried one of their free items. Did I cancel it? No, I didn&amp;rsquo;t think so. But also, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember actually signing up for it.
It got worse. Looking back at my previous statements I saw that I was also charged the previous month as well.</description></item><item><title>Moderation</title><link>/moderation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 09:43:35 -0600</pubDate><guid>/moderation/</guid><description>This quote by Oscar Wilde,
Everything in moderation, including moderation
is wrong.
By doing everything in moderation &amp;ndash; including moderation &amp;ndash; then that means you are overdoing moderation, which the quote forbids.
It should be amended:
Everything in moderation, excepting moderation</description></item><item><title>Books I read</title><link>/books-2008/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2008 15:00:45 -0700</pubDate><guid>/books-2008/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a comprehensive list of all the books that I read in 2008. This list does not include Sherman&amp;rsquo;s Lagoon or Get Fuzzy comic books, and it does not include textbooks.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ten Commandments (for a scientist)</title><link>/ten-commandments/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 15:19:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>/ten-commandments/</guid><description>Moses reached upon Mt. Sinai and was given the gift of the Ten Commandments which have dictated the fundamental rules of life ever since. Scrawled on the back of the Ten Commandments was actually another set of commandments that determined the virtuousness of science and the held commandments to follow when Moses led his people to the promised land to live fruitfully in the pursuit of scientific knowledge.
I. Thou shalt always vortex thy cells.</description></item><item><title>Genesis</title><link>/genesis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2008 21:54:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>/genesis/</guid><description>In the beginning, 10 to 20 times 109 years ago, there was a big bang. A hundredth of a second later electrons, photons and neutrinos appeared. Three minutes later the quarks of the fundamental particles formed into light nuclei, approximently 76% Hydrogen and 24% Helium. 300,000 years later G-d said, &amp;ldquo;Let there be light&amp;rdquo;; and the nuclei combined with electrons to form neutral atoms, making the universe transparent to photons.</description></item></channel></rss>