<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Coding on Your website</title><link>/keywords/coding/</link><description>Recent content in Coding on Your website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 09:41:01 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/keywords/coding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FIND3</title><link>/find3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 09:41:01 -0600</pubDate><guid>/find3/</guid><description>There is a new version of FIND now, called &amp;ldquo;FIND3.&amp;rdquo; Its public on Github now.
FIND is the Framework for Internal Navigation and Discovery. It is basically an indoor GPS for your house or business, using only a simple smartphone or laptop.
This is an idea I started thinking about 8 years ago and wrote the first code in PHP almost four years ago, dubbed version 0, as a proof-of-concept.</description></item><item><title>OSS divisions</title><link>/oss/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 09:04:40 -0600</pubDate><guid>/oss/</guid><description>There are two reasons I think its good for everyone to have a good division between &amp;ldquo;personal&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;corporate&amp;rdquo; use for open-source software (OSS).
If you, the OSS maintainer, are compensated, everyone benefits. While your time spent coding your OSS is valuable, I think the frictionless delivery of new features and bug fixes is something that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t go away. Since I&amp;rsquo;m not actively supporting you financially to work on this, I can only hope that someone does so I can benefit.</description></item><item><title>Why Go?</title><link>/why-go/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 09:48:59 -0600</pubDate><guid>/why-go/</guid><description>Lots of people ask me this question, and I end up writing the same answer over and over. I just wrote my plain answer here so I can just link to it. Don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to ask me other questions, though if you need. The basic answer is: because of time and money.
Coding in Go saves me time. When I write code, I often write run the program periodically to test it.</description></item></channel></rss>