<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2018 on Zack&#39;s Notablog</title><link>/written/2018/</link><description>Recent content in 2018 on Zack&#39;s Notablog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 10:28:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/written/2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installing Keybase on Chromebook</title><link>/installing-keybase-on-chromebook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 10:28:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>/installing-keybase-on-chromebook/</guid><description>Keybase is a great system for mounting a end-to-end encrypted filesystem. It also has an encrypted git feature which is great for storing secure information in repositories. While keybase has releases for most systems, that don&amp;rsquo;t have any releases for armh, of which Chromebooks fall.
With help from the keybase developers I have determined a way to get keybase up and running on a Chromebook in no time.
First install the pre-requisites:</description></item><item><title>My Favorite Vimrc</title><link>/my-favorite-vimrc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 10:25:45 -0700</pubDate><guid>/my-favorite-vimrc/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying writing in vim a lot more. There is a nice and simple way to make writing a lot easier (word-wrapping, nice color scheme). You can just make the following config file (save as ~/.vimrc):
func! WordProcessorMode() set columns=80 setlocal formatoptions=1 setlocal noexpandtab map j gj map k gk setlocal spell spelllang=en_us set complete+=s set formatprg=par setlocal wrap setlocal linebreak set foldcolumn=3 highlight Normal ctermfg=black ctermbg=grey hi NonText ctermfg=grey guifg=grey endfu com!</description></item><item><title>Hugo Craft</title><link>/hugocraft/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 23:12:08 -0600</pubDate><guid>/hugocraft/</guid><description>This is a ready-to-go Hugo-based blog publishing system. The styling has a lot of inspiration from the blog of Chris Siebenmann which I think excels in simplicity and minimalism. It uses mage for an OS-agnostic build system to make it easy to chain commands. It has a simple search and comments ready-to-go.
Features Integrated search (try it) Integrated comments at the bottom of each post Automatic image captioning using markdown Very fast (base page ~3.</description></item><item><title>Shallow `go get`</title><link>/shallow-go-get/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 07:00:57 -0700</pubDate><guid>/shallow-go-get/</guid><description>This is a little hack to use shallow clones for new git checkouts with go get. Unfortunately for Gophers, this has been an open issue for three years counting without a workable solution aside from patching the go toolchain yourself. This solution utilizes a git wrapper that determines if a pull/clone is happening and then makes sure it is shallow.
The wrapper is only a few lines of code, here&amp;rsquo;s the main.</description></item><item><title>Painters &amp; Hackers</title><link>/hackers-and-painters/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 22:22:02 -0700</pubDate><guid>/hackers-and-painters/</guid><description>Hacking1 and painting2 are both hobbies for me. I write programs for myself, to make things easier or just because they are fun to write. Few of these programs are useful3. More often I write useless programs, like a program to determine if random squiggles generate random numbers4. I started painting and coding about fifteen years ago5 for my own enjoyment. Along the way, though I&amp;rsquo;ve found some interesting comparisons about the reception of paintings and programs and whats it like to interact with other hackers and painters.</description></item><item><title>Painting of Red Heifer</title><link>/painting-red-heifer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 00:16:52 -0700</pubDate><guid>/painting-red-heifer/</guid><description>I started out with this great photo by James Wheeler.
I started out by sketching out the painting, loose white paint on red.
The background went very quickly, but I like how it turned out.
I spent most of the time on the head, but I think the light colors came out well.
If you have a picture that you&amp;rsquo;d like me to paint, leave a comment below.</description></item><item><title>Painting of roof with cats</title><link>/painting-roof/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:16:52 -0700</pubDate><guid>/painting-roof/</guid><description>I recently completed my biggest painting ever, 24&amp;rdquo; by 36&amp;rdquo; canvas with acrylic. I started out with a red canvas because I like how it can surround paintings to make them a little bolder (see some of my other paintings with a red background).
I picked out the starting picture - of a lone cat on a tiled roof in Jarandilla de la Vera, Spain. The original picture was taken by Fernando Nieto (check out his 500px, its great!</description></item><item><title>Analyzing 15 marathons over 4,000 days</title><link>/marathons-2018/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 23:07:45 -0700</pubDate><guid>/marathons-2018/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve done dozens of races and about 15 marathons since I started running. I&amp;rsquo;ve plotted my pace for 15 official marathons. Its quite obvious now that I&amp;rsquo;ve plateaued at a nominal pace. You can see that I got fast quite quickly - after about three years I hit my plateau of about 8 minutes per mile.
In my first three years of running I ran about 20 miles a week - sometimes more, sometimes less.</description></item><item><title>Average chocolate chip cookies</title><link>/average-cookies/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 20:57:15 -0700</pubDate><guid>/average-cookies/</guid><description>I recently wrote a program to determine consensus recipes. It scrapes the web for a thousand recipes for a given recipe (e.g. cookies), then clusters the recipes and finally computes an average ingredient list for each cluster. This idea was prompted by making brownies, because I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure whether to use cocoa, chocolate, or both. Turns out there is a recipe for each variation of brownie.
I decided to try out my software in the real world.</description></item><item><title>Consensus cookery</title><link>/consensus-cookery/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 09:41:01 -0600</pubDate><guid>/consensus-cookery/</guid><description>Sometimes when I want a recipe to cook something new I will find several recipes for the same thing and try to use them as a guide to generate an average or &amp;ldquo;consensus&amp;rdquo; recipe. This code should make it easy to generate consensus recipes (useful!) and also show variation between recipes (interesting!).
Finding a consensus recipe requires first clustering many recipes. This is because a single recipe (e.g. a recipe for brownies) might have many significant variations (e.</description></item><item><title>FIND3</title><link>/find3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 09:41:01 -0600</pubDate><guid>/find3/</guid><description>There is a new version of FIND now, called &amp;ldquo;FIND3.&amp;rdquo; Its public on Github now.
FIND is the Framework for Internal Navigation and Discovery. It is basically an indoor GPS for your house or business, using only a simple smartphone or laptop.
This is an idea I started thinking about 8 years ago and wrote the first code in PHP almost four years ago, dubbed version 0, as a proof-of-concept.</description></item></channel></rss>