<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2017 12 on Your website</title><link>/written/2017-12/</link><description>Recent content in 2017 12 on Your website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 05:48:49 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/written/2017-12/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Code I wrote</title><link>/code-i-wrote/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 05:48:49 -0700</pubDate><guid>/code-i-wrote/</guid><description>In 2017, I wrote 17 programs. Some or neat tools, some are playthings, and some are libraries for Go.
howmanypeoplearearound (2,967 stars) Count the number of people around you 👨 ‍ 👨 ‍ 👦 by monitoring wifi signals 🛰. PIanoAI (233 stars) Realtime piano learning and accompaniment from a Pi-powered AI 🎹. progressbar (215 stars) A really basic thread-safe progressbar for Golang applications. croc (207 stars) Easily get things from one computer to another 🐊.</description></item><item><title>Anonymous nonfiction</title><link>/anonfiction/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 07:16:03 -0700</pubDate><guid>/anonfiction/</guid><description>Sarcasm is the native language of the Internet. Unfortunately, since sarcasm is a close friend to cynicism, this can make the Internet a negative and disillusioning place. I decided to make an effort to make a place on the Internet that is more positive and reflective. This place would be where you can present your own story, anonymously and sincerely. The result was initially called &amp;ldquo;Stories, Incognito&amp;rdquo; but I later decided on the name &amp;ldquo;anonfiction&amp;rdquo; (i.</description></item><item><title>Podcasts I heard</title><link>/podcasts-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 09:41:01 -0600</pubDate><guid>/podcasts-2017/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve spent days sitting in a dark room looking into a microscope. Lots of the time I listen to music, but I&amp;rsquo;ve started to listen to podcasts. I&amp;rsquo;ve found a lot of great podcasts out there. I think my number one category of podcast is “the podcast about the small things.” Its always a welcome relief from the mainstream media which focuses more on the hyperbole of small things. I do like some news, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found some great podcasts that pitch the news in a more informal and friendly way.</description></item><item><title>Books I read</title><link>/books-2017/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 09:41:01 -0600</pubDate><guid>/books-2017/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve read about 15 books this year - not as many as I&amp;rsquo;d like (I read 40 in college), but I did a lot of magazine reading too (e.g. The Sun and The New Yorker). The books that I read can be classified into three major categories: non-fictional animal encounters, magical horror realism and fictional non-fiction.
The first main category are books I read in 2017 are about non-fictional animal encounters.</description></item><item><title>Painting from computer-generated primitives</title><link>/painting-primitives/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 18:25:57 -0700</pubDate><guid>/painting-primitives/</guid><description>Computers can do many amazing things with art, especially with the advent of neural networks1. In 2016, I saw some computer-generated art that inspired me to generate art as a human. The art I saw was a rendition of photos in primitives. Here&amp;rsquo;s an example (For much more, just follow @primitivepic):
These kinds of photos were generated using a computer program that tries to replicate a photo by slowly building up primitive shapes (ellipses, rectangles, triangles) of a single color until eventually enough different shapes and colors converge on the original image.</description></item></channel></rss>