<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Food on Your website</title><link>/tags/food/</link><description>Recent content in Food on Your website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 20:57:15 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/food/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Average chocolate chip cookies</title><link>/average-cookies/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 20:57:15 -0700</pubDate><guid>/average-cookies/</guid><description>I recently wrote a program to determine consensus recipes. It scrapes the web for a thousand recipes for a given recipe (e.g. cookies), then clusters the recipes and finally computes an average ingredient list for each cluster. This idea was prompted by making brownies, because I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure whether to use cocoa, chocolate, or both. Turns out there is a recipe for each variation of brownie.
I decided to try out my software in the real world.</description></item><item><title>Consensus cookery</title><link>/consensus-cookery/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 09:41:01 -0600</pubDate><guid>/consensus-cookery/</guid><description>Sometimes when I want a recipe to cook something new I will find several recipes for the same thing and try to use them as a guide to generate an average or &amp;ldquo;consensus&amp;rdquo; recipe. This code should make it easy to generate consensus recipes (useful!) and also show variation between recipes (interesting!).
Finding a consensus recipe requires first clustering many recipes. This is because a single recipe (e.g. a recipe for brownies) might have many significant variations (e.</description></item><item><title>Recurisve ingredients</title><link>/recursive-ingredients/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 19:19:15 -0700</pubDate><guid>/recursive-ingredients/</guid><description>What would happen if you made a recipe out of the ingredients for a recipe? What if you repeated this process over and over? I ended up doing this and generated the recipe that starts with the most basic ingredients - dirt, water and sun.
Here are the ingredients of my favorite recipe - a recipe for bread - that I have made almost every week during the past decade:</description></item></channel></rss>