<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ipfs on Zack&#39;s Notablog</title><link>/tags/ipfs/</link><description>Recent content in Ipfs on Zack&#39;s Notablog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 07:16:21 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/ipfs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>IPFS enabled personal internet archive</title><link>/ipfs-enabled-personal-internet-archive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 07:16:21 -0700</pubDate><guid>/ipfs-enabled-personal-internet-archive/</guid><description>There are some great ways to archive sites on the web. You can use archive.is or the Internet Archive. But, using the IPFS, its really easy to make your own hosted internet archive.
Say you found a cool website, like www.bzarg.com/p/how-a-kalman-filter-works-in-pictures/ which shows how a Kalman filter works. All you need to do is recursively download the site, with cross-domain assets, and then pin it to IPFS.
$ mkdir site1 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; cd site1 $ wget --restrict-file-names=windows -k --adjust-extension --span-hosts --convert-links --backup-converted --page-requisites http://www.</description></item><item><title>How to post a site to IPFS easily</title><link>/how-to-post-a-site-to-ipfs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 14:13:59 -0700</pubDate><guid>/how-to-post-a-site-to-ipfs/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a chicken-and-egg problem with IPFS to get pages to link to each other that is frusturating to IPFS users. To have the IPFS hash for the link you first need to get the IPFS hash of the other link. One way around this is to make all the URLs relative. This is a lot easier to do than you think.
First make a blog however you want and then host it locally, e.</description></item><item><title>Send a file with IPFS</title><link>/ipfs-transfer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 21:27:07 -0600</pubDate><guid>/ipfs-transfer/</guid><description>Sending a file with IPFS is fun (after all it is leveraging the peer-to-peer network and content-addressable blocks of data!) and easy.
Install IPFS Here is the basic instructions to install:
wget https://dist.ipfs.io/go-ipfs/v0.4.11/go-ipfs_v0.4.11_linux-amd64.tar.gz tar -xvzf go-ipfs* cd go-ipfs sudo ./install.sh ipfs init ipfs config Addresses.Gateway /ip4/0.0.0.0/tcp/9001 ipfs config Addresses.API /ip4/0.0.0.0/tcp/5001 The last two lines are useful for listening on LAN connected devices. The port 0.0.0.0 will let run the IPFS daemon on a different computer but still use the peer-to-peer portal from that computer.</description></item></channel></rss>