<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thoughts on Your website</title><link>/keywords/thoughts/</link><description>Recent content in Thoughts on Your website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 09:41:01 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/keywords/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Podcasts I heard</title><link>/podcasts-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 09:41:01 -0600</pubDate><guid>/podcasts-2017/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve spent days sitting in a dark room looking into a microscope. Lots of the time I listen to music, but I&amp;rsquo;ve started to listen to podcasts. I&amp;rsquo;ve found a lot of great podcasts out there. I think my number one category of podcast is “the podcast about the small things.” Its always a welcome relief from the mainstream media which focuses more on the hyperbole of small things. I do like some news, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found some great podcasts that pitch the news in a more informal and friendly way.</description></item><item><title>Books I read</title><link>/books-2017/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 09:41:01 -0600</pubDate><guid>/books-2017/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve read about 15 books this year - not as many as I&amp;rsquo;d like (I read 40 in college), but I did a lot of magazine reading too (e.g. The Sun and The New Yorker). The books that I read can be classified into three major categories: non-fictional animal encounters, magical horror realism and fictional non-fiction.
The first main category are books I read in 2017 are about non-fictional animal encounters.</description></item><item><title>Use social media without being social</title><link>/using-social-media/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 09:04:40 -0600</pubDate><guid>/using-social-media/</guid><description>Social media seems to be more about creating a persona that voicing your thoughts and ideas. Not thinking about public opinion enables you too emit thoughts without fear of judgment, which is why I&amp;rsquo;ve found it helpful to use social media without being social.
I make accounts on social media that are totally protected. I don&amp;rsquo;t follow anyone or let anyone follow me. I keep the account locked so no one can even visit it.</description></item><item><title>Autological words and quines</title><link>/quines/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 09:48:59 -0600</pubDate><guid>/quines/</guid><description>The word &amp;ldquo;noun&amp;rdquo; is a singular word. It is the only word that is what it is. Such a word is an &amp;ldquo;autological word&amp;rdquo; as they posses the property that they express. To determine if X is autological, it requires answering yes to any of the following questions:
Is X a X word? Is &amp;ldquo;X&amp;rdquo;, X? Some great examples of autological words are &amp;ldquo;polysyllabic&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;unhyphenated&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;harmless&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;pentasyllabic&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;unique&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Moderation</title><link>/moderation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 09:43:35 -0600</pubDate><guid>/moderation/</guid><description>This quote by Oscar Wilde,
Everything in moderation, including moderation
is wrong.
By doing everything in moderation &amp;ndash; including moderation &amp;ndash; then that means you are overdoing moderation, which the quote forbids.
It should be amended:
Everything in moderation, excepting moderation</description></item></channel></rss>