<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2018 06 on Zack&#39;s Notablog</title><link>/written/2018-06/</link><description>Recent content in 2018 06 on Zack&#39;s Notablog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 10:01:55 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/written/2018-06/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Self-hosting with fossil, an alternative to git</title><link>/fossil/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 10:01:55 -0700</pubDate><guid>/fossil/</guid><description>Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket are all web interfaces for git. They all do similar things that add on features that aren&amp;rsquo;t implicit in git, like issues and wiki, etc.
Unbeknownst to some, fossil is an alternative to git that actually has built-in issues, wiki, and easily self-hosts. This is a quickstart to get started with hosting and cloning fossil repos. The official quickstart is very good, although I realized a few tricks in getting the hosting to work on HTTPS behind a reverse-proxy, which are described here.</description></item><item><title>IPFS enabled personal internet archive</title><link>/ipfs-enabled-personal-internet-archive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 07:16:21 -0700</pubDate><guid>/ipfs-enabled-personal-internet-archive/</guid><description>There are some great ways to archive sites on the web. You can use archive.is or the Internet Archive. But, using the IPFS, its really easy to make your own hosted internet archive.
Say you found a cool website, like www.bzarg.com/p/how-a-kalman-filter-works-in-pictures/ which shows how a Kalman filter works. All you need to do is recursively download the site, with cross-domain assets, and then pin it to IPFS.
$ mkdir site1 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; cd site1 $ wget --restrict-file-names=windows -k --adjust-extension --span-hosts --convert-links --backup-converted --page-requisites http://www.</description></item><item><title>How to post a site to IPFS easily</title><link>/how-to-post-a-site-to-ipfs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 14:13:59 -0700</pubDate><guid>/how-to-post-a-site-to-ipfs/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a chicken-and-egg problem with IPFS to get pages to link to each other that is frusturating to IPFS users. To have the IPFS hash for the link you first need to get the IPFS hash of the other link. One way around this is to make all the URLs relative. This is a lot easier to do than you think.
First make a blog however you want and then host it locally, e.</description></item></channel></rss>